《少年谢尔顿》前情提要
Previously, on Young Sheldon...
我跟约翰·斯特吉斯博士一直有通信
I've been corresponding with Dr. John Sturgis
他在东德克萨斯理工大学教书
at East Texas Tech.
他说我能去旁听他的课
He said I could audit his course.
康妮  我很希望能再跟你见面
Connie, I would like to see you again.
或许有机会我们可以一起吃个晚饭
Perhaps we could have dinner sometime.
太好了  我们很愿意
Yes, we would love that.
我们会愿意吗
We would?
如果他们结婚了  我们家族的聪明人数量
If they get married, we immediately double
就可以瞬间加倍呢
the number of smart people in our family.
你好  斯特吉斯博士
Hello, Dr. Sturgis.
你好  谢尔顿
Hello, Sheldon.
你能想象你住在这里吗  我就能
Can you see yourself living here? I can.
热狗丁跟意面的比例完美
Mmm. Good ratio of hot dog chunks to spaghetti.
我一直在实验完美比例  很高兴你注意到了
I've been experimenting. Glad you noticed.
孩子们  洗手吃饭啦
Kids! Wash up for dinner!
会是谁来按门铃啊
Now, who on earth is that?
不许你把热狗丁全挑出来吃了
And don't be picking out all the chunks.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm a little late.
我的裤腿卡自行车链条里了
My pant leg got stuck in the chain.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是约翰·斯特吉斯
I'm John Sturgis.
谢尔顿邀请我来共进晚餐
Sheldon invited me to dinner.
好的  您先请进吧
Okay. Um, come in, I guess.
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
来了
Coming!
这是给你的
This is for you.
是起司与熏香肠
It's cheese and summer sausages.
谢谢
Thank you.
熏香肠就代表这不需要放冰箱冷藏
Summer sausage means it doesn't need to be refrigerated.
是这样吗
Is that so?
是的
It is.
好的  谢尔顿
Okay. Sheldon?
斯特吉斯博士  欢迎你来
Dr. Sturgis, welcome.
谢谢  谢尔顿
Thank you, Sheldon.
谢尔顿  你不觉得你应该先让我知道
Sheldon, you think you might've let me know
你邀请了人来共进晚餐吗
you invited company over for dinner?
我想过告诉你  但我怕你会拒绝
I did think about it, but I was afraid you might say no.
来看看我的火车模型吧
Come see my train set.
好
All right!
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
我的老天啊
Good Lord.
你是说他就这么突然出现在你家吗
You mean he just showed up out of nowhere?
他现在在车库里跟谢尔顿玩火车呢
Yep. He's out in the garage playing trains with Sheldon.
你的头发为什么是湿的
Why's your hair wet?
如果你真想知道  我本来是在做水中有氧
If you must know, I was doing my water aerobics,
然后我的泳帽掉了
and my swimming cap fell off.
这位斯特吉斯兄台没先跟你说过吗
This Sturgis fella didn't say a word to you?
要是有  你觉得我还会去基督教青年会里的
If he did, do you think I would have been doing frog kicks
游泳池中蛙式蹬腿吗
at the YMCA?
你看起来很棒
You look great.
32毫米模型铁道轨距的火车最棒了
O gauge trains are definitely the best.
是的  没错
Oh, yes, they are.
真是个意外之喜啊
Oh, well, what a pleasant surprise.
太好了  你也来啦
Oh, good. You're here, too.
是啊
I am.
你们都准备好吃晚饭了吗
Are y'all about ready for dinner?
我好了
I am.
那我们快去吧
Well, then, let's go.
姥姥  你闻起来有氯的味道
Meemaw, you smell like chlorine.
你说出来干嘛
Why say it?
你说的是真的
You weren't kidding.
意面配热狗丁真是超好吃
Spaghetti and hot dogs is delightful.
我妈找出完美比例后又更棒了
Even better since Mom perfected the chunk ratio.
斯特吉斯博士  谢尔顿跟我们说
So, Dr. Sturgis, Sheldon tells us
你在大学里是客座教授
you're a guest professor at the university.
是的
I am. ‭Hmm.
这表示你只是暂时待在这个城市吗
Does that mean that you're only here temporarily?
目前的计划是这样
Well, that's the plan for now.
但如果有理由留下  我也可以留
But I could be enticed to stay.
姥姥  我觉得他话中有话
Meemaw, I do believe there was subtext there.
你有听出弦外之音吗
Did you pick up on it?
有的
Yeah.
我说你话中有话没理解错吧
Was I correct to infer there was subtext there?
理解很正确
You were.
好的  那一切没事
Okay, we're all good.
真不敢相信他们让我来小孩桌吃饭
I can't believe they're making me sit and eat at the kiddie table.
这里比较好
It's better here.
好在哪
How?
不用饭前祷告  不用被逼吃蔬菜
We don't have to pray, eat our vegetables,
而且可以骂脏话
and we can curse.
或许你说的有道理吧
Hmm. Maybe you're right.
当然有啊  你个傻逼
Course I am, you ass-face.
斯特吉斯博士  你觉得人类会有把重力
Dr. Sturgis, do you think we're ever going to unify gravity
跟其他三种基本力统一的一天吗
with the other three fundamental forces?
我的冰箱上面有个便利贴
I have a sticky note on my refrigerator
天天提醒我要做到这件事
which reminds me every day to do just that.
你是什么时候开始把研究重心
When did you decide to focus your research
-放在量子...  -谢尔顿  我觉得
- on quantum... ‭- Um, Sheldon, I think
你有点霸占人家聊天的机会了
you're kind of dominating the conversation.
你何不让姥姥跟斯特吉斯博士聊聊呢
Why don't you let your meemaw talk to Dr. Sturgis.
抱歉  你们聊吧
Oh, I'm sorry. By all means.
谢谢
Thank you.
-康妮  -怎么了  约翰
- Connie? ‭- Yes, John.
你是故意让自己有氯的味道的吗
Do you smell like chlorine on purpose?
你确定不用我送你回家吗
You sure I can't give you a ride home?
你的自行车可以放到我小卡车后面一起啊
I can throw your bike in the back of my pickup truck.
谢谢好意  我挺喜欢夜晚的空气
Thank you, no. I-I enjoy the night air.
而且热狗与意面富含热量
Plus, hot dogs and spaghetti is a highly caloric event
需要自己做点有氧运动来消耗掉
that demands an aerobic effort on my part.
很高兴今晚能有机会跟您共进晚餐
Well, it was a pleasure spending the evening with you.
有机会欢迎再来
We should do it again sometime.
那太好了  什么时候呢
Great. When?
明晚怎么样
How about tomorrow?
这样吧  我们之后再讨论
You know what, we'll figure it out.
来  我陪你走到你的自行车吧
Come on, let me see you to your Schwinn.
再见啦
Bye.
晚安
Good night. ‭
这是我在这个家里吃过
Well, that was the most stimulating dinner
最振奋人心的一顿晚餐了
I've ever had in this house.
你开心就好
Glad you enjoyed it.
那个男人真是我的人生榜样啊
That man is a true role model.
恭喜你终于找到了一个男性榜样啊
Well, it's nice you finally got a man you can look up to.
是啊  我深有体会
Oh, believe me, I know.
你是想全憋在心里
You gonna keep it all bottled up,
-还是你想说出来  -什么
- or you want to talk about it? - ‭What?
我没事啦
I'm fine.
没什么好聊的
There's nothing to talk about.
-你确定吗  -确定
- You sure? ‭- Yeah.
好好睡吧
Sweet dreams.
你知道你自己很想讲
You know you want to talk about it.
你也看到了
You saw it.
我的亲生儿子不觉得我能当他的榜样
My own son can't even imagine me being a role model?
你让我心里怎么舒坦
How am I supposed to be okay with that?
你是小乔治的人生榜样啊
You're a role model for Georgie.
曾经是
I used to be.
他现在只想长大变成像男演员托尼·丹扎
Now he wants to grow up and be Tony Danza.
你忘了自己还有个女儿
Did you forget you have a daughter
而她如果有个良好的男性榜样也会受益良多吗
who would really benefit from having a good man to look up to?
老天爷啊
Oh, dear Lord.
你还真忘了
You did forget. ‭
我没忘  我只是...
I didn't forget. I just...
我只是不知道怎么跟她相处
I don't know how to spend time with her.
又不是让你登天  乔治
It ain't rocket science, George.
她就是个小女孩
She's a little girl.
问她想做什么
Ask her what she wants to do,
然后陪她一起做
and then do it with her.
好吧  我应该可以
Oh, yeah. I suppose.
相信我  你能陪她她会很开心的
Trust me. She'll be thrilled to spend some time with you.
好啦
Okay.
我再试试看
Yeah, I'll give it a try.
等我陪她...  做她想做的事情的时候
Hey, when we do, you know, whatever it is she likes to do,
你也会在一旁陪着吧
you're gonna be there, right?
不会啊
No.
好吧  这事瞬间难了
Well, this just got harder.
姥姥
Meemaw?
Meemaw!
什么事
What?
我专门去研究了
I've been researching things
我们可以跟斯特吉斯博士一起做的事
that you and I can do with Dr. Sturgis.
今晚在莱斯大学有一堂课
There's a lecture tonight at Rice University called
"我们银河的中心在发生什么事"
"What's happening at the center of our galaxy."
你先停一下
Let me just stop you right there.
别放心  我知道银河中心的情况
Don't worry. I know what's happening at the center,
但我不会剧透你的
but I would never spoil it for you.
听我说  我知道你十分希望
Look, I know you're invested
我跟约翰能有感情发展
in me and John having a relationship,
我的意思也不是我们不会
and I'm not saying we won't.
但如果你整天碍事  我们就很难有发展
But it ain't gonna happen with you always underfoot.
我碍手碍脚了吗
Have I been underfoot?
亲爱的  大人们想要多了解彼此
Honey, in order for grown-ups to get to know each other,
就需要有单独相处的时间
they need to have some alone time.
如果我发誓保持缄默  能让我在一旁待着吗
What if I'm around, but I took a vow of silence?
回家吃你的早饭去
Go home and have your breakfast.
她说大人们想多了解彼此
And then she said for grown-ups to get to know each other,
就需要有单独相处的时间
they have to have time alone.
很有道理  还有呢
Makes sense. What else?
貌似我当个碍事精对浪漫有害
Apparently my being underfoot isn't conducive to romance.
你的消息很有用
This is very helpful.
谢谢你
Thank you.
乐意为你效劳
I'm at your service.
塞莱斯特  你为什么总爱上坏男人
Oh, Celeste, why do you always fall for bad boys?
爸爸你来啦
Hi, Dad.
你在干嘛呢
What you doing?
我做错事了吗
Am I in trouble?
没有没有  我就来关心你一下
No, no. Just-just checking in on you.
为什么
Why?
因为你是我女儿  而且我爱你啊
'Cause you're my daughter and I love you.
越说越尴尬了
This is getting weird.
是啊  我是在想...
It is. I was just thinking that, uh,
你跟我呢...  不太常一起相处
you and me, you know, we don't spend much time together.
我们应该找点事一起做
You know, we should find something to do,
就我跟你
just-just two of us.
-比如什么  -你说啊
- Like what? - ‭You tell me.
你觉得什么有趣
What-what sounds fun?
我想你请我出去吃晚餐
I'd like to be taken to dinner.
很好  上哪吃
Great. Where?
去德州最时髦高档的餐厅
To the fanciest restaurant in all of Texas.
是...
Which is...?
红龙虾餐厅  海陆大总汇
Red Lobster, where the surf meets the turf.
美式连锁休闲餐馆  主要吃海鲜与各种肉排
一言为定
You got it.
谢谢老爸
Thanks, Dad.
妈  你得带我出去买东西
Mom, you got to take me shopping!
我要买条新裙子
I need a dress!
是谁
Yeah?
康妮  是我约翰·斯特吉斯
Connie, this is John Sturgis.
你好啊  约翰·斯特吉斯
Well, hello, John Sturgis.
你好吗
How are you?
我今早吃桃子被桃核崩了牙
I chipped a tooth on a peach pit this morning,
除此之外一切都好
but otherwise, I'm okay.
很好  你好就好
Good. Good to hear it.
下一件事情呢
Next order of business.
我是想邀请你今晚一起吃饭
I would like to have dinner with you tonight,
就我们俩人单独
just the two of us.
这听起来很不错
Oh, well, that sounds nice.
你有什么计划
What'd you have in mind?
我想来你家为你做一顿四川菜
I'd like to come to your house and cook you a Szechuan feast.
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry, a what?
四川菜
Szechuan.
一种中式料理风格
It's a style of Chinese cooking I learned
是我在中国旅游时学会的
when I was traveling through China.
真棒  我很愿意
Well, wonderful. I would love that.
太好了  你家有炒菜锅吗
Great. Do you have a wok?
没有呢
I do not.
没关系
Not a problem.
我有便携炒菜锅
I have a travel wok.
好的
Okay.
六点怎么样
Uh, so, uh, what do you say about 6:00?
就这么说定了
It's a date.
好极了
Terrific.
对了  我们别告诉谢尔顿
Oh, and, um, let's not mention this to Sheldon
他就不会来碍事了
so as to keep him from being underfoot.
你是不是跟他联系过
Have you been talking to him?
是啊  晚点见
I have. See you later.
不过是去红龙虾餐厅  我有必要盛装打扮吗
Do I really need to get dressed up to go to Red Lobster?
你盛装打扮是为了女儿不是为了吃饭
You're getting dressed up for your daughter.
这是新衬衣  记得要个围兜
And that's a new shirt, so be sure to ask for a bib.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
你要穿这样去吃晚餐吗
You're going to dinner wearing that?
你是想说她看起来真美吧
I think you mean she looks beautiful.
你看起来真美
You look beautiful.
谢谢赞美  乔治
Why thank you, George.
你今晚还是叫我爸爸如何
How 'bout we stick with "dad" tonight?
行吧  但你要叫我米丽莎
Okay, but you call me Melissa.
你先请  米丽莎
After you, Melissa.
谢了  乔治
Thanks, George.
老天
Oh, my.
我知道  我看起来好像忍者神龟
I know, I look like a Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtle.
快进来吧
Well, come on in.
谢尔顿  进厨房吃饭吧
Sheldon, come in the kitchen for dinner.
-我能在这里吃吗  -为什么
- Can I eat out here? - Why?
斯特吉斯教授在跟姥姥进行晚餐约会
Dr. Sturgis is having a dinner date with Meemaw.
我不想错过
I don't want to miss it.
好吧
Fine.
在那段时间里  我看到三辆车经过
During that time, I saw three cars drive by
还看到一只浣熊拖走一片比萨
and a raccoon dragging a slice of pizza.
两位  谢谢
Uh, table for two.
没问题
No problem.
容我帮您
Allow me.
准了
You are allowed.
谢谢
Thank you.
是的  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
恕我冒昧
If I may.
你觉得怎么样
So what do you think?
我觉得我们穿得太寒酸了
I think we might be underdressed.
一顿成功的四川晚餐的秘诀
The trick to a successful Szechuan dinner
就是四川花椒
is the Szechuan pepper.
好吧
Okay.
你可能会发现
Now, you may notice
你的嘴唇和舌头发麻
your lips and tongue getting numb.
那我们为什么要吃
Then why are we eating it?
因为很好吃啊
'Cause it's yummy.
好吧
Sure.
所以你为什么去环游中国了
So, what were you doing wandering around China?
我不做研究或教书的时候
Well, when I'm not doing research or teaching,
我喜欢走上较少前人踏过之路
I enjoy taking the path less traveled.
我猜是那路还是单车路吧
I'm guessing it's a bike path.
还真是呢
As a matter of fact, it was. ‭
在中国人人都骑自行车
Everybody in China rides bicycles.
太棒了
It's fantastic.
-你去长城了吗  -我去了
- Did you see the Great Wall? - ‭I did.
有趣的事实
Interesting fact:
长城底下埋了许多
it's filled with the dead bodies
建筑工人的尸体
of the people who built it.
不会吧
You don't say.
有成千上万具尸体
Hundreds of thousands of them.
来尝一口
Here, taste.
如果只有我们俩  我为什么不能边吃边看电视
If it's just the two of us, why can't I eat watching TV?
因为你在跟你妈一起吃饭
'Cause you're having dinner with your mother
这是我们交心的好机会
and it's a chance for us to talk.
谢尔顿就在边吃饭边看窗外啊
Sheldon's having dinner and looking out the window.
想要我叫他进来一起吃吗
Want me to have him join us?
不想
No.
那就别抱怨了
Then quit complaining.
你想聊什么
So what do you want to talk about?
我也不知道
Um, I don't know.
上学怎么样了
How's school?
那里可是学校  就是一坨屎
It's school; it's a turd fest.
真好
Charming.
你在跟谁交往吗
Are you dating anyone?
没有  没人配得上我
Nah, nobody up to my standards.
当然了
Sure.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
当然可以  你想问什么都行
Course, you can ask me anything.
你跟爸结婚时是不是已经怀上我了
Were you pregnant with me when you married Dad?
你为什么会问这个
Um... why would you ask that?
谢尔顿说的
Sheldon said so.
谢尔顿怎么会知道
How would Sheldon know?
他算过了
He did the math.
算什么
What math?
他说我的生日
He said the time between my birthday
和你们举行婚礼那天相差六个月
and your wedding day was six months.
是啊
Um... yeah.
那是因为你...
That's because you...
是早产儿
were born premature.
我看过我的出生证
I've seen my birth certificate,
上面写着我出生时是8斤巨婴
it said I weighed nine pounds.
没错
Yes, that's true.
你是个大胖早产儿
You were a big fat preemie.
我们聊点别的吧
Let's talk about something else.
为什么
Why?
因为我非常想换话题
'Cause I'd very much like to.
然后海瑟一号就说
And then Heather B said she didn't want
她以后不想跟海瑟二号玩绳球了
to play tetherball with Heather M anymore.
等等  有两个海瑟吗
Wait. Th-There's two Heathers?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
哪个是哪个来着
Which one's which?
海瑟一号是自大狂
Heather B is stuck up.
海瑟二号以前也是自大狂
Heather M used to be stuck up,
但后来她戴上了脊椎侧弯支架
but then she got a scoliosis brace.
或许她不应该玩绳球
Maybe she shouldn't be playing tetherball.
海瑟一号就是这么说的
That's what Heather B said.
很美味
This is delicious,
但你没夸张  真的好辣
but you were not kidding about the spice.
我都快辣出满头汗了
I'm about to break a sweat here.
有一个有趣的小知识
Well, here's something you might find interesting.
辣的食物通常出自天气较热的地方
Spicy food is typically found in warmer climates
因为吃辣能让人出汗
because it induces sweating,
从而让大家凉快下来
which in turn, cools people off.
那流鼻水对我有什么好处
So what does the runny nose do for me?
让我有机会
It allows me to, uh,
对你殷勤地献上我的手帕
gallantly offer you my handkerchief.
你真绅士
You are such a gentleman.
我年轻的时候
When I was younger,
看了一本介绍礼仪的书
I read a book on etiquette.
我从上面学到
That's how I know
如果我有机会去梵蒂冈受到接见
that if I ever have an audience at the Vatican,
我应该穿上晚礼服或男便装上衣
I should wear evening attire or a sack coat.
我不知道男便装上衣是什么
I don't know what a sack coat is,
但你穿上一定很帅气
but I'm sure you'd look handsome in it.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚上骑车回去很远
You know, it's a long bike ride at night.
如果你想的话
If you want...
欢迎你留下来过夜
you're welcome to stay.
没事  我的单车有车头灯
No, it's fine, I-I have a headlight on my bicycle.
当然了  当然
Oh, sure, sure.
不过  据说好像会下雨
Although, I hear it might rain.
不用担心  我有折叠雨衣
No worries. I have a pocket poncho.
好吧
So you do.
约翰
John.
我是在邀请你留下来过夜
I'm inviting you to spend the night.
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
早产婴儿不是都要
Don't they make babies that are born too soon
留院察看吗
stay in the hospital?
通常是的  但你出生时
Normally, yes, but you were born
有一头秀发
with such a great head full of hair
医院就让我们带你回家了
that they sent you home with us.
这是你刚才说的唯一合理的话
That's the first thing you've said that makes sense.
我很高兴我们一起吃晚餐  感觉很好
I'm glad we had dinner; this was nice.
是啊  很好玩
Yeah, fun stuff.
可不能错过《成长没烦恼》
Well, don't want to miss Who's The Boss.
主啊  原谅我说谎了
Lord, forgive me for lying.
等他30岁时我再告诉他真相  阿门
I'll tell him the truth when he's 30. Amen.
您的龙虾  女士
Your lobster, madam.
谢谢
Thank you.
需要我帮她切开吗
Would you like me to open it for her?
我来就好  谢谢
Oh, I got it, thanks.
-你还好吧  -这玩意好吓人
- You all right? ‭- This thing's freaking me out.
来吧  我来帮你
Here, let me help you with that.
挪一下  好了
Here. Okay.
秘诀在于别跟它对看
The trick is not to make eye contact.
跟它说去
Tell him.
来
Here.
好了  我们把龙虾钳子扯下来
All right, now, we just... snap her off
像这样  啪
like that... pop.
拿上工具
Grab this guy here,
把钳子夹裂
and we crack the claw.
然后取出一些虾肉
And then you take out a little meat...
蘸一些牛油酱
dunk it in some butter,
再放到嘴里
and then you eat it.
哎哟妈呀
Holy moly.
很好吃  对吧
It's good, huh?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
接下来你自己弄吧
I'll leave you to it.
别走  陪我坐
No. Sit with me.
好吧
Okay.
等我长大后  我每晚都要吃龙虾
When I grow up, I'm gonna eat lobster every night.
宝贝  那你得好好读书  上所好学校
Well, hon, you better stay in school and get a good education.
我想着我就嫁给有钱人好了
I was thinking I'd just marry a rich guy.
行啊  这也是一条路
Sure, that's a way to go.
或是嫁给红龙虾餐厅的员工
Or a guy who works at Red Lobster.
那也是一条路
That's another way to go.
你都没怎么说话  没什么问题吧
You seem quiet. Is everything okay?
你对我没兴趣吗
Are you not interested in me?
当然有了  我对你很有兴趣
Of course I am. I'm very interested.
那为什么...
Then how come when I...
我邀请你留下来过夜  你却拒绝我
I invited you to spend the night, I got rejected?
我确实拒绝了  对吧
I did do that, didn't I?
当然了
Good Lord, yes.
我可以解释
I can explain.
愿闻其详
Please do.
我不希望你认为在我心目中
I didn't want you to think that I would think
你是那种就因为
that you were the sort of woman
我煮了四川菜给你吃
who would engage in coitus
你就会跟我交媾的人
simply because I cooked you a Szechuan dinner.
你不解释还比较好
It was better before you explained.
好吧  那我换一种方式
All right, let me try a different tack.
康妮
Connie.
老天
Oh, boy.
你愿意赏光  今晚与我发生亲密关系吗
Would you honor me with an evening of intimate relations?
这方式确实与众不同
Well, that is a different tack.
看起来情势一片大好
This is very promising.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
斯特吉斯博士的单车还停在姥姥家
Dr. Sturgis's bike is still at Meemaw's.
那又如何
So?
说明他也很可能还在姥姥家
That means he probably is, too.
你需要有自己的生活
You need to get a life.
他出现了
There he is.
妈妈  妈妈  妈妈
Mom, Mom, Mom.
-出什么事了  -怎么了
- What's wrong? - What's going on?
斯特吉斯博士和姥姥第一次一起过夜了
Dr. Sturgis and Meemaw had their first sleepover.
这是他们恋爱关系的重大进展
It's a big step in their relationship.
我要去恭喜他们
I'm going to go congratulate them.
先穿上外套  外面很冷
Hey, put on a jacket, it's chilly out.
好的
Will do!
你应该说他不准去
Or try saying he can't go.
不用穿了  你不准去
Oh, never mind, you can't go!
外套后面的话我都没听见
The last thing I heard was jacket!